All right so now let's tackle what exactly is HVM mill and how do we use it to structure websites.
So no matter what you use as your browser it could be chrome.
It could be Safari or Firefox.
They all have a single purpose and that's to interpret your files such as your HDMI files or CSSA files
or javascript files into a Web site that should be displayed.
So for example we've got a little bit of HVM l code here that says that our web site should have a title
code.
Hello.
And in the body there should be a heading that says Hello world.
So if we pass that code into our browser it will open it and display it like so with the title of the
Web site usually on the top and that H-1 or that big Hedding showing up in the body of our website.
So before we dive deep into this it's really important to remember that H Tim L is the foundation of
all Web sites.
So for example you won't see Web sites are created using just a CSSA file or just a javascript file
but you can create Web sites using just an HMO file.
Now it might not look great.
It'll probably look like it came from the 90s but it does enable your website to display tags or various
elements such as images or forms or tables depending on how you code up the T.M. file.
So each channel stands for hypertext markup language and the really important part here is the word
markup because there's many markup languages.
For example you might have heard of things such as XML Extensible Markup Language or DML generalized
markup language and all of these languages share a common history.
They're based off some markup that used to be put into manuscripts where editors would mark up the manuscript
and either specify changes to the author or specify structure and layout to the publishers.
So for example you might have the squiggly line that shows the publishers that this part should be printed
in bold or this part should be printed in a tallis and HMO works in much the same way.
You can specify the layout and structure of your website by using HVM l tags.
So if you head over to your browser and go to a Web site called Code Pennicott IO then we can have a
look and have a play around with real life live DML so you don't have to sign up.
Just head over to code Penda IO and then hit create new pen and then we're going to change the view
to a format like this.
So this is the live version of our website and these are the places where we're going to put our code.
So as you can see code penned that you put in HCM LCS us and javascript which will together get interpreted
and get shown on the left as your Web site.
Now as we're only working with HDMI at the moment I'm going to minimize the CSSA and Javascript sections
and I'm just going to work from the HD M-L section.
Now we're going to need some text to work with or have something which we can give structure to.
If you head over to Gutenburg to auxlang ebook slash 1 6 6 1 you get taken to the adventures of Sherlock
Holmes by Arthur Conan Doyle.
So one of my favorite books of all time.
If you have a look down here you can see that you can view the book as plain text.
All you can read this book on line as HMO.
So this is what the plain text looks like.
It has all of the text in the book but absolutely no structure.
But when we have a look at the H.T. a mouse file you can see that it has laid out the book with a structure
that is more human readable.
And this is what we're going to replicate using HCM.
So if you go ahead and just copy this part The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle
and you copy and and place it into your pen.
So in the H.M.S. here now you can see that all of these tags gets put onto the screen with absolutely
no structure.
And in order for this to start looking like this we're going to start adding a little bit of HMO.
So the first thing we can see is that this is the largest heading on the page so we can make our website
look like that.
Also by adding an H1 tag into our HMO so the tags start with angular brackets and end with angular brackets
and in the middle is the type of element or the type of type you want to use.
Now it's really important that when you open ties that also closed them because as you can see here
I've got an open TYG.
But I have yet to close it and it thinks that the entire contents of my page should be made into the
largest heading possible and that's not what I want.
I only wanted for this section the Adventures of Sherlock Holmes.
So in order to close the tie it's the same angle brackets.
But then I have to use a forward slash and then write H-1.
So now only this part is an H1 or a large heading.
Now if we have a look at the other parts I would say that this word buy is a little bit smaller than
the author's name.
So let's structure this as a heading or so.
But let's make it a subtitle so let's make it a slightly smaller heading and to do that we can simply
wrap this text around an H to tag it and now we have Sir Arthur Conan Doyle as a heading but in a smaller
size and shown with less importance than the big title.
So now finally we have this word by.
And I reckon that's one size smaller than this heading so let's go ahead and wrap this inside an H 3.
So I hope you're starting to get the gist.
The heading tags get smaller as the number goes up.
So for example if I changed this to an age 4 it gets even smaller h 5 smaller still and all the way
until age 6 which is the smallest font size for the heading element.
Now if you keep going to H 7 you'll notice that it doesn't do anything anymore.
It doesn't change the heading size and that's because the heading elements only go from 8 1 to 8 6.
Now how do I know that.
I hear you ask.
So this is a good point in the course to introduce documentation.
And the reason why I'm talking about it so early on is because of how important it is to your journey
as a web developer.
So one of the key skills in becoming a great web developer or fact any sort of programmer is getting
good at finding out how you can help yourself and a lot of that involves getting good at googling.
How do you find the specific piece of information that's going to help you achieve what it is that you
want or help you understand what it is that you want to know.
So in this case we're talking about headings and we are using HMO and I'm going to add in the name of
the documentation that I preferred to use which is EMDIN and it stands for the Mozilla developer network.
So the same people who made Firefox for example.
So if I go ahead and hit enter.
You see a whole bunch of results come up.
And the most relevant for us is the H-1 to age 6 and it talks about headings.
So if we click on that you can learn more about the heading elements used in Tamil and they even have
example code snippets that show you what it would look like rendered in a browser.
Now there's a couple of sources for documentation.
One is of course MT-NW Another one is called W3 schools.
So let's see if we tried to have three schools with HDMI.
And we're talking about headings right.
See what we get here.
So she M-L headings is the first result that comes up.
And similarly you've got the code examples you've got the results and you've got a little bit of notes
that tell you how you should be using your headings.
So both of these places have a lot of really useful usage notes and it's worth reading through your
first coming across a particular element.
That way you'll have a good foundation of knowledge when you start to build and create your own websites.
So I want to show you one last resource that I quite like using which is called Def docs.
I know.
And this is basic web site that puts together a lot of the useful documentation in a structure that
I find to be quite handy.
So if we have a look inside the HCM L5 tab and we go into the elements we can see that there's a total
of 135 elements and if you scroll down you can see that we've got 8 1 through age 6.
And if you click on any of these then it brings up actually the MDA and documentation so you can see
that it's similar to what we saw on MDA but it's just structured in a very simple way and it's very
easy to follow.
So that's definitely a Web site that's worth bookmarking.
So if we head back over to our age e-mail file We're going to change that back to an H-3 which is an
age old tag that actually exists as opposed to something like h 9.
So the next thing that we need to do in order to better replicate this Web site is to add some space
between these lines.
Now in a word processor such as Word or google docs you'll be able to simply just hit a few times or
hit return a few times and get that speccing show up.
Now unfortunately in HVM Well it doesn't quite work like that.
It's a little bit more complicated in order to create that spacing.
We actually have to use an 80 shemale element called a line break and it's written like so.
And the interesting thing about this HDMI element is that it doesn't require both an open and a closed
hug.
So we have the H 1 3 2 h 6 tags.
You can see that we started out by marking the text with an H1 and then we close it off with a closing
tag but the line break element works all by itself and you can even put it inside like so to make this
part go onto a new line.
Now this is a good time point to review the anatomy of HTL tags.