All right.
So let's talk about the anatomy of NHT M-L tag and break it down to its component parts so that we can
actually understand how they're structured and how we can use them.
So we've written 20:00 elements like so.
So here we have the words hello world and they're enclosed by an opening tag and a closing tag.
And in between those tags is the content that we want to apply that structure to.
So if you think back to the days of marking down a manuscript it's exactly the same as putting down
a quickly line underneath certain words or phrases and asking the publisher to make it bolded to affect
the structure of certain parts of the text.
Now in this case the publisher just happens to be our browser so these tags make requests to the browser
asking it to structure and display our plain text in the way that the web designer wanted it to be shown.
Now the other type of tag that we just saw are tags that don't have a closing tag.
They're expressed simply like so.
And these are called self-closing tags.
And we've seen that with the brake tag.
And there's a few more others that work like this also.
Now how do we find out if something requires a closing tag.
Or is self-closing.
Well this is where we head to the documentation again.
So if we have a look at the documentation for the heading elements you can see that there's this part
in the table that says Tag a mission and it says that both the starting and ending tags are mandatory
so that you can specify which portion of your text you want to apply this structure to.
Now we have a look at the B or the line break element.
You can see that under Tiga mission.
It says that it must have a start tag and must not have an end tag.
So this is how we find out how we write our tanks.
Now while we here I want to introduce you to another element called the horizontal rule or the H R tag.
And this will allow us to create these horizontal lines above and below our portion of text.
So as you can see in the documentation under tagon mission it also says that it must not have an end
tag.
So this is also a self-closing tag.
So let's head back over to our pen so that we can add these two horizontal rules above and below all
text.
So the first one is going to go here
and the last one is going to go here so you can see that our Web page now has two horizontal lines above
and below our main portion of text.
Now if we have a closer look at this Web site you can see that there are horizontal rule is a little
bit thicker than ours.
So how can we make ours look more like theirs.
Now this is part where I show you a neat trick on any web page that you open in Chrome.
You can simply right click on the element that you're interested in and click inspect in order to look
at the HMO and CSSA code that's being rendered in the background by the browser so you can see here
they've got an H.R. element.
Horizontal rule.
But they've got Also all of this going on afterwards.
So what exactly is that.
Now we know that the first part of the tag is the HTL element and it's B.
Shaw whatever it is that you want to use.
Now the second part inside the angle bracket or inside or tag is new.
And this is called an HMO attribute and it basically gives more information to the browser to specify
modifications to that HDMI element.
So in this case we're saying that we want a horizontal rule but we wanted in size 3.
Now what is size 3 mean and how do we know that we have these attributes available to us.
You've guessed that we're going back to the documentation.
Now I know we're making a big deal about going to the documentation but it really really is an important
skill understanding and being able to look up the documentation being familiar with the structure of
it and where to look.
In order to find out how to implement or do certain things.
So if we have a look at our documentation for each other you can see that there's this section called
attributes and that's what we spoke about just now.
The attribute comes after the attribute comes after the main HDMI element from and is separated from
the element by a single space.
In this case the horizontal rule element has actually quite a few attributes including a line so you
can specify whether if you want your hars onto line to align to the left or line to the right or be
centered you can specify the color of the horizontal rule.
You can set weather if you want the horizontal rules have shading or not and you can also set the height
in pixels of that horizontal rule which is what we saw earlier on over here.
So in this case the reason why they're horizontal rule looks different to ours is because ours is by
default only one pixel high or one pixel in size whereas there's if you inspect in the HD M-L is 3 pixels
in height and they've also specified no shade i.e. no shading to the horizontal rule.
So if we want to make our website a seamless copy of what we see here then we also have to specify those
attributes.
So if you remember the horizontal rule is a self-closing tag.
And so inside the tie we're going to make a space and then we're going to specify the name of the attribute
which we know from the documentation to be called the size attribute.
And we're going to set it to equal three pixels and then we're going to specify that it is no shade
i.e. no shading.
And we know all of this from the documentation.
So now once our code updates you can see that this brand new hars onto a rule looks completely different
from what it was before.
And we can copy this over to the top as well so that all horizontal rules look exactly the same as what
we've got over here.
So now we've seen HDMI elements that require an opening tag as well as a closing tag.
We've also seen T.M. elements that have a self-closing tag.
And finally we've seen that HDMI elements can also have an attribute where you can specify modifications
to the default element.
Now all we need is just to add one final tag code center to or a simple file and we would have now faithfully
copied what this Web site looks like.
So you can have a look through the eight CML by remember right clicking and inspecting in Chrome.
And you can look through to see how they've structured the rest of the document as well.
Now this is a good point to mention.
Our first challenge so we've got this code pen now where we've been messing around with the HMO.
Now you can either save this anonymously or you can create a free encode pen in order to be able to
access this later on.
But I want you to create a brand new pen and this pen is going to be our code playbook and you're going
to use this document as an interactive notebook if you will.
And I want you to document here all the new things that you've learnt as we progress through the course.
So for example in this and the last lesson we learn about the H1 tag.
So in our code playbook the first thing that's going to go in is your H-1 tag and you can say that this
is a level one heading created using the H1 tag we can go ahead and close it off and you can look through
the documentation to perhaps copy some of these code snippets over but make sure that whenever you're
copying pasting code that you understand what it is that you've copied over you understand what the
code does.
There's nothing worse than copying and pasting code that breaks your Web site because you don't understand
what you've put in there so we can go ahead and then modify each of these so that when we're creating
our own Web sites and we want to come back to our playbook and have it as a point of reference then
we'll be able to see easily at a glance all of the elements that we've used and that we've learnt about
before.
So my challenge to you is to create your very own code playbook and to start keeping notes on all the
things that you're learning in this course.
Now sometimes with certain elements for example the line break you don't have to put any text inside
a line break in the same way that we've done so for the H-1 tag.
So this is a point where you can use a comment instead.
In your aged him l file so comments are portions of tags which are marked out to be ignored by the browser.
And they usually places where you write notes to yourself or notes to fellow programmers who might be
looking at your code.
So NHT M-L we create a comment by using the angle Bacchante a exclamation mark two dashes and then to
close off the comment.
We use another two dashes and a closing angle bracket and everything in between here is a common.
You can see that usually it gets highlighted in a different color and none of it gets interpreted into
the web page.
So this is where you can put sections for your notes.
For example self-closing tags.
You can make it into several paragraphs just by putting the closing tag at the bottom and you can write
notes on the elements as we come across them and keep this for your own reference.
By the time when you're ready to create your own web site it will be a goldmine of a resource to jog
your memory on all of the lessons that you've learned.
So in the next lesson we're going to be building our very first web site and it's going to be really
really awesome because we're going to be using a real text editor and we're going to be putting that
Web site live onto the Internet.
So there's all of that and more yet to come.
So I will see you on the next lesson.