Right.
So in this lesson we're going to be building our very first web site now because we've only talked about
HDMI also for how to structure Web sites using Timah elements and we haven't yet gotten to the part
where we've learnt about styling using CSSA then we're kind of limited in terms of the kind of Web sites
that we can make.
But Finot our Web sites are going to be right up there with the Internet Titans but just way back in
1997.
So do you remember what Yahoo looked like when it first launched.
Or do you remember what Google looked like when it first came out.
No I don't remember.
Well it was a great Web site.
I can show you exactly that.
And it's called The Internet Archive Wayback Machine and you can find it at web dot archive dot org.
Now in here you just enter the realm of a Web site that you were interested in say Yahoo dot com.
Then it shows you what this Web site looks like all the way from 1996 to current day which is 2017.
Now let's have a look at what Yahoo looked like originally on the first day it was crowed.
So 17th of October 1996.
So let's go ahead and click on that snapshot.
And this is exactly what it looks like.
So if we close off this frame you can see it's almost like as if you've time traveled back to 1996 when
Yahoo first launched and you were visiting this Web site for the first time.
Now as you can see most of this is just pure HMO.
It's a lot of structure and a lot of formatting but it looks really ugly.
But it's OK because it's a great place to get started with.
So this is the sort of web site that we're going to be building by the end of this module.
Now I hate to say Oh but this looks terrible.
We're in 2017.
Surely nobody builds web sites like this anymore.
Well this is an interesting anecdote that you might not know if you have a look at some of the world's
top computer science professors and you look at their personal pages that they've built.
They all look a little bit like this not so dissimilar from the Web sites in 1996.
So this is Thomas Coleman who's a serious algorithm guy and this is a Web site of John Kleinberg.
Another huge name computer science professor and of course the king himself.
Donald Earth has a website that looks like this.
So if it's good enough for these computer science Titans then it's probably good enough also for our
very first web site.
So by the end of this module we're going to build a website that looks much like this something that
we can put up online to show what we've done.
OCV as well as our hobbies and things that we like to do.
So you can use it as a personal site or somewhere to list your CV online.
So I hope you're excited because I'm super excited and once you're ready let's go ahead and create our
very first web site.